Can you grow a small trading account
with very little amounts of money? Yes,
it's something that could be done, but
it's not the typical way on how to make
money from the markets. Not the way on
how you're going to extract it and
become a profitable trader. [music] Now,
I've been very fortunate to take a
complete stranger that also happened to
be a student to help them take $1,000 to
$100,000. That was a very aggressive
small account that we scaled after a
couple blown accounts. We managed to
[music] successfully do it in about 3 to
4 months. Now, I want to set the
expectations straight. This video is not
that. This is on how to properly scale
smaller [music] accounts to where it's
going to eventually end up being a
bigger account. This is not taking $10
into [music] generational wealth. This
is not the video for that. If that's
what you think it is, uncclick it. This
is not it. You want to learn how to
scale your small accounts, make sure to
watch to the end and I'm going to teach
you how to do that properly. Now, in
this video, I have with me a very
special guest, which is Upnil.
>> Thank you so much, bro.
>> No, thank you for coming. Honestly,
>> thank Abnail is one of my successful
students and he's actually been hosted
previously on my swing trading lab
podcast where he successfully has gotten
multiple payouts from proper accounts
and [music] he's mainly known for being
a prop firm trader and scaling his
proper account but he wants to learn how
to scale small accounts and I'm like
what better way to teach you how to do
that where you can be here representing
the viewers asking questions
interrupting where you don't understand
right so there's no pressure any point
you have any questions feel free to just
jump in and ask me okay
>> awesome bro
>> you ready to dive in Yes, both.
>> Okay, let's do it. Today we're going to
be talking about three very key
components. The first one is going to be
creating a proper plan to scale a small
account, which it's similar but very
different from a profit account, right?
So, creating a proper plan to scale
>> a small
account. That's going to be the first
thing we're going to focus on. The
second thing which is basically the
backbone of a whole entire scaling of a
small account is understanding
risk management. Risk management
on a small account. And then third, last
but not least, no plan and no risk
management is absolutely nothing without
the [music] technicals. You need to have
your proper technicals for a small
account, right? There's a specific type
of strategy that you need to use to be
able to actually scale your small
account when it comes to the technicals.
So, we're going to be breaking down all
three of these components. The proper
plan that you need to have to scale, the
risk management behind a small account,
which is what's going to make or break
traders, and what trades you should be
focusing on and what trades you should
not be focusing on. Okay, so let's start
off with the plan to scale a small
account, right? So, a small account
typically could be anywhere from, let's
call it $500 to about $2,000, right?
This is typically what I would consider
a small account when I was working at
Dunkin Donuts.
>> Awesome.
>> This is what I believe that everybody
that gets involved in trading has access
to some way or another, right? If it's
not 500, somewhere in the middle, this
is what a small account would be like.
So when it comes to trading a small
account, the most important thing is
that you are okay, you are okay to
completely
lose [music] this money, right? So you
need to set the expectation straight.
When you are trading with a small
account, you're obviously going to have
to take higher risk and in turn when you
take higher risk, you can obviously
lose. So when you go deposit this small
account, think of it as if this money
was already lost. That way you're not
emotionally attached to it. You don't
revenge trade and you don't get lost on
having to [music] force more trades when
your account is smaller, right? So
picture the money that you deposit into
this account that is completely gone.
And that way you take trades that make
more sense. You're not chasing [music]
the money. So that's the first step to
the plan. So you get completely removed
from any types of emotion and you're
only focused on what you should be
focusing on. Now, when you have your
small account, you should be looking to
take anywhere from one to two trades a
week max because every single trade that
you want to take has to be the highest
probability trade setup, right? You
can't afford testing your strategy. You
can't afford a loss because when you
take a loss, it's going to set you back
very far in the account and it's going
to be very hard for you to make it back.
It's not like a profit account if you
were to risk 2 3%. So, let's say you
want to take three different types of
trades on your profit account risking
1%. If two of them lose at 1%, one of
them wins plus 2% with the riskreward,
you're at break even.
>> Yeah.
>> This is not like that. You can't even
take three trades at the same time cuz
you literally blow the account.
>> Of course.
>> So, the max amount of trades that you
want to take in a week is anywhere from
one to two trades.
>> If you can even take one, even better.
[music] Now these trades that you're
taking that are one to two trades a week
the most important thing is going to be
the RR
>> okay
>> which is what
>> the risk risk to reward
>> correct so RR is risk to
>> reward
>> reward now typically the normal that you
would have for a profit account or for
any other account could be anywhere from
a one to two to maybe a 1 to 2.5
>> which is great right this is a
profitable risk-to-reward you can have
five trades trades that you lose. And
out of these five trades that you lose,
the five trades that you win will
obviously outweigh the losses cuz all of
this right here will be minus five. And
if this has a 1 to2 risk-to-reward
>> plus 10, you're obviously left with an
overall profit of five, right?
>> So with these small accounts, the most
and crucial and important thing is going
to be that your risk-to-reward begins
from a 1 to three and above. So, your
risk-to-reward needs to be at a 1 to
three plus.
>> The larger the risk-to-reward, the
better,
>> the better
>> because you want to make sure that one,
since you're being very selective with
the trades that you're taking, you can
maximize those wins as much as you can.
Now, this goes back into having the best
quality trades. And we'll break that
down once we get to the third step.
>> But this is the base core plan of
scaling any small account,
>> accepting that you have a small account
and that this money is basically gone.
>> Okay? Second, you need to focus on
quality over quantity.
>> And that having a high risk-to-reward is
what's going to actually scale the
account for you. Any questions?
>> So, how much is the 1% of the total of
the account? Let's say if we choose
$2,000 account, how much will you risk
on the first trade?
>> Yeah. So, that actually leads me perfect
to the next part, which is going to be
the risk management for this account.
So, we don't typically do 1% when we're
risking on these small accounts, right?
Because if you do 1% of $2,000,
it's
>> it's 20 bucks.
>> 20 bucks, right? Like, you know, that's
not even going to pay for a McChick
nowadays, right?
>> So, when it comes to the risk management
of the accounts and what you risk,
that's where the backbone of this is
going to be built, right? So, now we're
going into the second topic, which is
going to be the backbone of growing any
small account and is the most important,
which is risk
management. Right. Don't mind my
handwriting. Right. Yeah.
>> So, risk management is by far going to
be the most important thing. So, for
this example's purposes, let's kind of
go right in the middle of the account
balance that we decide to start off
with. Let's say that we have $1,000
starting balance, right? This is our
starting balance with our account. So,
we understand that we have to take
anywhere from one to two trades a week.
[music] And we understand that our
risk-to-reward needs to be a minimum of
a 1 to three plus.
>> Yeah. So on these one to two trades, how
much do we risk? Great question. Now
typically what we would do as a prop
firm trader is the typical risk is you
know the the standard to stay within the
rules is 1 to 2%. Right? So this 1 to 2%
is literally the max that you can
possibly do because your draw down is a
total of 8% on some prop firms or 10% on
other prop firms. Now that is because
the prop firm sets those rules and you
have to create your own rules so you
don't obviously
>> you have the account
>> preach them.
>> Now here we set our own rules which is
good and bad because since we're setting
our own rules we can obviously make a
mistake
>> and we're the ones holding ourselves
accountable. Now, for the prop firms,
the standard is a percentage because you
have higher amounts of money, right? Or
the $100,000 account. If you were to
risk 1%,
>> it's $1,000.
>> It's $1,000, right? So, that's a
significant amount of money, right?
$1,000. You catch a one to three risk
reward. It's $3,000. It's a great amount
of money. And that's just risking 1%.
So, when you have anything over, I like
to say [music] $25,000
is where you should focus on the
percentage [music] game, which is what
is happening here. Anything below
$25,000, it's all the [music] money
game.
>> Money game,
>> right? So, this is where we're going to
transition the risk management into the
money game. So, risk management when
you're scaling a small account is no
longer percentage. It's the money game.
So, this is where you need to figure
out, okay, you know what? For the
$1,000, I want to create the base that I
want to risk $250
or I want to create the base it be $350.
It's whatever you feel comfortable with,
but you have to make sure that you have
at least four or five trades in you
before you would obviously lose the
account. Yeah.
>> Now again, this is very high risk, but
it's the only way to scale the account.
So these $1,000, you go very high risk
at the starting point and then as you
start creating a bigger account, you
lower that risk so you're not prone to
blowing this account. So this is where
the money game comes in. And you have to
find what you're comfortable with
risking on the first couple of trades.
So what would you feel comfortable with
risking on these $1,000?
>> Probably 35% at $350.
>> Okay. $350. Okay, perfect. So now the
next the the first trade that you're
going to take on scaling your small
account is the most important trade.
>> Yeah.
>> Because that trade will either make or
break you.
>> Yeah.
>> It's going to either set you back or
it's going to give you off to a great
start. Right. So you decided that you
wanted to risk $350. [music]
Now if you catch a one to three
risk-to-reward to that, it's basically
$1,000. Yeah.
>> Right. So this is what [music] you're
going to risk.
And then this is reward,
>> your potential reward, right? After fees
and after everything, going to have
about $1,000 because we're always going
for a one, correct? A one to three RR.
Now, the best way that I like to explain
your first trade, it's going to be with
a punch card. And I actually learned
this from Mr. Warren Buffett, right? So,
let's say I give you this punch card.
And these are all the trades
you have
to take
in your life. So the trades that you can
take in your life are on this punch card
[music] right here. There's going to be
a total of about 15
trades inside of here. 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 16 17 18 19 20. Let's call it 20
trades. So, what you should do when it
comes to taking a trade in [music] your
small account is as is if you were to
have a punch card like this. Punch card.
I'm terrible at writing. Right. M.
>> So once you mark off all of these
trades,
>> okay,
>> you're done. You can never trade ever
again in your life. So what is that
going to make you do? That's going to
make you be very selective on every
single trade that you're going to take.
You're going to think two times, three
times, four times before you enter that
first trade because of the importance
and the impact that this risk has on
your $1,000.
>> Yeah. So, whenever you go take your
first trade, whatever it is that you
decide to risk, you need to make sure
that that trade is 100% worth risking
those 350 bucks.
>> Okay?
>> Because the moment that you do take that
trade, you're down one punch. You got 19
left to go.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you need to make sure that that
probability is a very high probability
trade setup. And very high probability
trade setups that can potentially give
you a one to three risk-to-reward don't
come every single week, right? Right?
They can come maybe once a week, maybe
once every two weeks.
>> And this is not the time to learn a
strategy. This is not where you learn
>> how to trade.
>> No, not at all. This is once you already
have some type of understanding how
trading works and you've made some
money, you've lost some money, and you
want to try a different approach,
whether it's prop firm or personal, this
is where you go and put that into
practice. But you do not learn a
strategy off of doing this approach. So,
if you're learning a strategy right now
and you're an beginner or even
intermediates, go watch other videos,
get educated. this is not the moment for
you.
>> Right? So, this is for someone like an
has been trading for some time, has made
some money, and is ready to take on a
different type of trading. Or maybe
you've passed some profit accounts,
you've made it to that funded stage, but
you never get a payout because of the
rules. Maybe because the rules aren't
set in your favor. Trying something like
this where you can set the rules for
yourself.
>> Yeah.
>> So, back to the punch card. So, let's
say the first trade that you're going to
take wins, right? Because you were very
patient. You were very selective with
your trade. Cool. So now your $1,000 you
have basically taken it to let's call it
$2,000.
Now that's fantastic, right? Because
you've technically doubled your account
by just technically risking 30% of your
account.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is great. Now all you have to do
is then determine what is my goal with
these,000. Is my goal to take it to
10,000, 50,000, 100,000, a million,
right? What's your goal? You have to be
realistic with what you're trying to do
and how much experience you have. So
what what would you say would be your
goal with these $1,000?
>> Let's say 100K.
>> 100K. Okay. So your goal to take $1,000
to $100,000 is [music] very optimistic
goal.
>> Like it's very challenging to do
something like that. Is it possible?
Sure. Just very high risk. Now you have
to determine how fast do you want to get
there. Do you want to get there in 6
months? Do you want to get there in a
year? What is something that you
envision yourself doing?
>> Probably in 6 months. in 6 months. Okay,
so taking $1,000 to $100,000 in 6 months
is possible. Now, you have to do the
math reverse. So, let's say your goal is
$100,000, right? We're going to keep our
punch card here cuz it's very important.
So, let's say $100,000, right? Is your
goal right now. You are currently at
$2,000 because you just won a trade. So,
this trade that you just won is your
balance. Now this goal right here that
you want to have in 6 months. How many
weeks in 6 months?
>> 24.
>> 24 weeks, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So now what you have to do is
divide this in weeks. So let's do like
this. For example, let's do one week, 2
weeks, 3 weeks, four weeks, 5 weeks, 6
weeks, 7 weeks, 9 weeks, 10 weeks,
4 weeks, 15, 14, 19, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20,
21, 22, 23, 24. Right. Yeah. 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24
Okay, 25, right? 24 [music] weeks. So
your first week, you've already taken a
$1,000
to $2,000, right? So now this starting
balance is 2K. Now your end goal is
$100,000, right? So that's your end goal
by week 24. Now, what you have to do is
go backwards. If technically you just
doubled your account, obviously if you
were to go 2K, 4K, 4K to 8K, 8K to 16,
16 to 36, 36 to 60, no, what is it?
>> 32 64
>> 64 64. Right there is where you would be
at 120. That's if you were to double
your account every single week. You'd
basically be there halfway.
>> Four, five, six, seven weeks.
>> Seven weeks, which is a very aggressive
approach. And that is very unrealistic.
Could happen. Yes. Because you're
setting goals on a weekly process.
That's how I did it when I took this
student. It took me three months to do
it. Now with you, I would try and do I
would try and achieve it by this time.
So I would do the math to where I can
make it make sense to hit by the 24
weeks. So for example, instead of taking
2K to 4K, maybe we take 2K to 3K.
>> Okay?
>> And then if we take the 3K instead of to
6K, we take it to
>> four and a half. four and a half 5k and
that 5k instead of 10 we take it to
seven and then you slowly do the math
until then it gets to that point. So
then now you're no longer risking $350
[music]
or 35% on your account. What you would
end up risking is going to be let's call
it $150 from your account or call it
$200 on the account now. So now what
you're risking is 10% rather than 35%.
So if you were to lose a trade you don't
have a major setback.
>> No. Does that make sense?
>> Yeah.
>> Now, this is definitely possible. But if
you were to look at this, how many weeks
do we have here? We have 24 weeks.
>> Yes.
>> And how many trades do you have on your
punch card?
>> 20.
>> 19 because you already took your first
trade.
>> So, is this possible? Obviously, sure.
We can add a little bit more trades to
our punch card and we can obviously make
it 24. Then that means that you would
have to win every single trade for the
next 23 trades, which honestly, it's
pretty much impossible, right? it it
could it happen? Sure. But if I were to
grade this from one out of 10, I would
give this a 10 out of a difficulty,
right? So, let's set a real more
realistic example on growing a small
account. Again, if you're looking to
flip an account, that is not what this
video is about. I just want to show you
how if you have a goal, you can work it
backwards, even if it's something as
optimistic as this. So let's set a
realistic
example when it comes to actually
scaling a small account rather than
flipping. Right? So for example, let's
say our goal is to scale our account
from $1,000 to $10,000. Right? So our
goal is to take these $1,000 to $10,000.
Now the same principle applies. What do
you feel comfortable with risking
knowing that this is your goal rather
than say $100,000? probably
15% to 20% 150 bucks or 200 bucks.
>> Okay, so 150 bucks, right? If you lose
150 bucks of a,000, you're still left
with 850 700 after some fees, you'll be
fine, right? So you're okay with
risking, let's call it 150 bucks. Now,
same exact principle applies. This 150
bucks with a one to three risk-to-reward
will then give you your $450.
$450 will then be your account left,
right? So you have $1,450.
Same exact principle applies. You can
either continue to stay with the same
risk or you can decide to lower it
>> or you can decide to raise it. The
consistency of this risk management is
entirely up to you. There's no proper
strategy on when you should risk more,
risk less depending on the technicals,
and that's what I'm going to be showing
you next. But for now, the basis on how
to actually scale to an account is by
doing the math backwards by when you
want to hit it and focusing on quality
trade setups. If you were to lose two
trade setups in a row, so for example,
let's say our first two trades, our
first three trades are losses, you're
probably down so bad into the account.
>> Yeah.
>> That you might either have to redeposit
into it
>> or change the goal completely in terms
of time.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. But let's say your first three
trades are winning trades. Well, then
you might want to continue with that
same risk management or maybe even
double down. But let's say you have an
inconsistent start where you have one
loss, then you have a win, and then you
have a loss. Now things could get
tricky. And the most important thing is
finding something that you're
comfortable with whether you win or
lose, whether you lose lose win or win
win. So basically what you are telling
me is what is going to get me to the
goal is the patience not how aggressive
I am with the trades because in prop
firms example for me I used to do a lot
of aggressive trades in this case no
>> basically.
>> No yeah yeah no aggressive trades at all
like the patience is going to pay right
that that that's our whole reasoning for
the punch card which it forces us to
focus on quality trade setups. We're not
testing anything new here. You're not
learning anything. You know exactly what
you're looking for when it comes to the
markets in terms of the strategy and
then all you have to do is just execute
and you don't have to think about it.
>> Awesome.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> So that leads us perfectly to the next
part which is going to be the
technicals, the actual strategy. What
are you going what types of trades are
you going to be taking? Are you going to
be taking counter trend trades? Are you
going to be taking protrend trades? So
let's break everything down right now so
you can focus on the best quality trade
setups. Now going into the third point
which is going to be the technicals.
Right
>> now this is where some people are going
to probably overlook this and maybe skip
it but it's probably the most important
part.
>> It is
>> because you can have the money, you can
have the risk management, but if you
don't know the types of trades that
you're taking,
>> you don't got nothing.
>> Yeah.
>> Right.
>> So there's for me personally two
different types of trades. The first
trade is going to be a pro trend trade
and then we have the other which is
going to be a counter
trend trade. Right? So there's two
different types of trades. If this
market is all going bullish, you want to
continue buying with it. If this market
is going bullish, you want to predict
the high of it to catch the sell.
High risk,
risk, low risk. Now, people get both of
these confused. Some people have this
gamblers mindset and they think, "Oh,
high risk equals high reward." I don't
know why they think that makes sense.
>> Okay,
>> it's completely wrong. High risk in
trading does not equal high reward.
>> It actually equals exactly what it is.
>> Yeah,
>> high risk. Low risk equals high reward
because the odds of you losing a trade
that has a low risk of losing means that
you have a high reward. So meaning you
can risk more on lowrisk trades because
it can make you more money. If the odds
of you losing are a lot less, makes more
sense
>> to risk more.
>> To risk more. Like for example, right
now if Mike Tyson were to get into the
ring with I don't know, say someone who
>> you.
>> Okay. Yeah. You're going to bet on me
all day, right? I'm the I'm going to
win. You know, that's a that's a lowrisk
bet. The odds of me winning Mike Tyson
are very high, right? You know, at least
I I like [laughter] to think that. Well,
that's the example that I want to make.
If you know that one is going to have
more odds of winning than the other, you
just simply bet heavier on that side
because that risk the odds of you losing
it are not there.
>> So this is consisted of protrend trades
and countertrend trades. Now protrend
trades and countertrend trades as you
know we're going to educate the people
here today are broken down by three
simple time frames. The first going to
be the weekly, the second going to be
the daily and then the third the 4hour
of course. Now both of these are the
same but different. The weekly time
frame will let you know obviously where
markets can go for the next two to three
weeks, the daily for the next couple of
days and the 4 hour for the next couple
of days. Now, a protrend trade, right,
which was the example that we're going
to set here. Pro trend trade is going to
be when all of these are working
together. When this one, this one, and
this one are all the same. Meaning this
market, for example,
is bullish.
This daily time frame, for example, is
bullish. And then the 4hour time frame
is also bullish. Right? This is the
exact same time frame. Let's call this
example right here Euro USD for example,
right? So EuroUSD right now the weekly
time frame is bullish. Daily time frame
is bullish. 4hour time frame is bullish.
The most logical thing to do right now
>> is buy, right? Just course it makes
sense to buy because you're going to be
trading with the trend.
>> This is what would make this trade a low
risk trade
>> because you're trading with the trend.
Now, obviously, if the market is all the
way at a high point right now, you don't
want to trade at a high point.
>> Yeah.
>> Makes no sense. It's like buying Bitcoin
when it's at the high. What was the
height of Bitcoin?
>> 126.
>> Yeah.
>> Why would you buy Bitcoin at the highest
point it's ever been, right? Like,
>> it's like right now gold. What's gold at
right now? Like 5,000.
>> 5,000. Yeah. Today was 5,00
>> 5,100.
>> There's still people buying up there.
That makes no sense to me. Like, you
don't ever want to buy something at the
highest point. So yes, you are bullish,
you are at the highest point, but you
want to wait for what I like to call a
discount, which is also that
retracement. So first you need to
identify if the market has these three
time frames together, right? So let's
say for example, this time frame is
bullish, bullish, bullish, right? This
is great. What we want is this type of
discount for this market to have a
retracement. Now we want for the
retracement to happen only on the weekly
and on the daily.
>> Okay?
>> Right? We want this retracement to come
back to a weekly area of interest or a
daily area of interest. So this weekly
area of interest is the same as here as
on the daily area of interest. That's
what we're anticipating to come back.
That's what we're anticipating. This is
where the weekly area of interest is now
anticipating. Right? So if you notice
for price to come back to this weekly
area of interest, this still remains as
the higher low. That still remains
higher high as the higher high, right?
Still very bullish. This is still the
higher low. That's still the higher
high. We're still very bullish. But now
if this market comes down here, guess
what? This used to be the higher low.
This used to be the higher high. We now
shifted bearish. So now the 4hour time
frame is no longer in our favor. The
weekly is still bullish.
The daily is still bullish. And now the
4hour time frame is technically
bearish. So now we don't have a full
protrend trade because we're missing the
4hour time frame. So, this would now
make this go from a lowrisk trade to a
mid risk trade because technically, yes,
we still have this time frame in our
favor and this one, but we're missing
the third one.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, remember, you have a punch card
that has 20 trades that you can only
take.
>> Can you take this trade
>> if you want, you know?
>> Yeah,
>> you can do whatever you want at the end
of the day, right?
>> Does it make sense to take the trade?
No, probably not, right? Because if you
have other trades that have higher
probability and you can get this time
frame to be bullish in your favor as
well, you want to wait for that. Yeah,
>> this is where what you ask me the
patience game. Patience. You want to
make sure that you can wait for that
proper entry before entering the trade.
So now that the 4hour came bearish into
this area, what you would have to wait
for is for this to shift bullish again.
So then you can have the 4 hour go
bullish back with the daily, back with
the weekly.
>> Yeah. And then at that point once that
shifts bullish you have all three time
frames in sync go ahead and decide to
take your first trade. So this is the
basics of trading with the trend as a
protrend trade. Now let me identify to
you high-risk trade which is technically
a lowreward trade. Now we have a
low risk trade which is also equivalent
to a counter
>> trend
trade also known as a CTT counter trend
trade.
>> All right same thing it will always
[snorts] be consisted of the weekly the
daily and the 4 hour. Correct? Right. So
we have weekly daily and then the 4
hour. Now for this example, we're going
to set a market that for example is like
this. So that's the weekly time frame.
It was bullish at one point. We shifted
bearish.
>> This is the daily time frame. The daily
time frame will obviously have a lot
more structure,
right? And the daily time frame is
technically like this. So the daily time
frame is that bullish or bearish? It's a
little bit tricky, but
>> I would say bearish.
>> Bearish. So look, if that's the lower
high, that's the lower low, lower high,
lower low. That technically it's a new
lower low, lower high. Technically, it's
bullish now.
>> Bullish. Okay.
>> Bullish. So then the 4 hour, we're just
going to keep it simple. We're only
going to draw this market structure
right here.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's the 4hour structure right
there. So we're only focusing on that.
Correct. So now on the weekly time
frame, you have the weekly time frame
that is currently
>> bearish.
>> Yeah.
>> Daily is bullish.
>> And then 4our is bullish. bullish. Now,
this is a counter trend trade. Why is
this a counter trend trade? Well,
because technically, yes, you could buy
because you have both of these time
frames in sync.
>> But you have to understand where you're
buying to. You're buying right into this
weekly structure level, this weekly area
of interest where price is literally
setting up the perfect sell to continue
going to the downside. So yes, you could
be buying with the daily time frame
going up. You could be buying with the 4
hour going up, but you're buying it
straight into a resistance that price is
going to reject from to then head to the
downside.
>> So this would be a counter trend trade
because some people only like to look at
the 4 hour and the daily and they
completely disregard the weekly and then
they question why they lose. They
question why they're wrong and what
they're doing wrong. Well, what they're
doing wrong is not looking at the higher
time frame. The higher time frame will
always dictate the direction of where
the lower time frames will go.
>> Yeah,
>> it takes seven days or technically five
days for one candlestick to form on the
weekly. That's a lot stronger than one
that takes 24 hours or one that takes 4
hours.
>> So, if you have a trade that is
technically bullish on both of these
time frames and you're going against the
weekly trend, which is what you're doing
here, that is a counter trend trade.
That is a lowrisk trade.
>> Yeah. So, this would not make any sense
to trade in in your punch card. Yeah,
it's absolutely pointless.
>> If you would want to take this trade,
what you would have to do is wait for
the daily to shift bearish, wait for the
4 hour to shift bearish, and then now
all of this turns from bullish to then
bearish, and then you're trading with
the trend.
>> Yeah.
>> Any questions? I know you understand
this at this point.
>> Yeah, I understand. Yes. So, no
question.
>> All right. So, now that you understand
this, I'm going to let you into some
secrets on how to scale a small account,
right? A lot of people are curious on
what's my secrets behind it. And this is
my plan, right? This is what I do no
matter what. This is my way in executing
scaling any small account. Now, I have a
very unique secret or hacks on to
scaling a small account that a lot of
people for some reason they overlook,
right? So these are going to be some
secrets
to scale
a small
account, right? So the first secret
which is the most obvious is going to be
leverage. Now leverage is very important
when scaling small accounts simply
because it will give you more access to
your money. So, this is for example,
this has happened to me in the past
where I've tried to take $1,000 and I've
tried to take it to $10,000, but I had a
one to 100 leverage. The problem with
that is that I decided to start risking
$100 on the account. What ended up
happening is that I started losing
three, four trades in a row. When my
account was at about $500,
I could no longer risk $100. Yeah,
>> I was only able to risk
>> 50ucks
>> 40 50 bucks because of the spread what I
had available in margin. So if I were to
swap out my leverage from a 1 to 100 to
let's say a 1 to 500, I would have never
had that problem. So I could have
continued my same risk that I had from
the start. I could have kept it going
even when I lost four or five trades in
a row because here I have much more
access to my money. So leverage is good
and bad. It's good because it lets you,
for example, in a situation like this,
stick to your exact same risk
management. Bad because if I would have
started off with these thousands and I
decided to risk the full th,000,
>> you overtrade or over.
>> I could pretty much do that. But if you
have the risk management in place how we
previously said before, technically
there's no risk behind this. Mhm.
>> It's almost like having a car that can
go 200 m an hour and you never go the
full 200 m an hour. You just go up to
the speed limit just really fast.
>> Exactly what this would be. Or it's like
let's say you have a credit card with a
limit of a million dollars. Doesn't mean
you're going to spend a million dollar.
You just have access to it. So whenever
you want, you don't have to call the
bank to raise your limit or approve some
things. Yeah.
>> So this is the exact same thing. you
just have a lot much more access to the
current money that you already have in
the platform.
>> So basically this is this is the best
leverage you recommend us watching to
scale accounts.
>> I think you do not need more than a 1 to
500.
>> I have actually I'm lying. I have traded
with a 1 to 1,000 before.
>> Okay.
>> And there there's no difference.
>> Oh
>> I feel like I mean there could be I just
didn't risk as much that the 1 to 1000
let me. 1 to 500 leverage is
>> perfect.
>> It's overkill. It's perfect. You You
don't need more than that. Awesome.
>> That will be enough for you to be able
to risk what you want to risk for sure.
So now, this is one of my first secrets,
right, when it comes to just trading
account as a whole. My second secret is
no trades
on Sundays.
No trades from Thursday on now.
>> And where's that?
>> Okay, great. no trades on Sunday because
when the market opens on Sunday, the
volume is very low and typically the
volume won't really kick into the
beginning of New York session on Monday.
So, there's no reason on entering a
trade when there's no volume because you
don't need to be overexposed on a trade
that simply makes no sense. And that
will save you one fees that you're going
to pay when you take your trade on your
small account that you need to save as
much money as you possibly can. And two,
if you do take a trade on Sunday, by the
time you hold it on Tuesday, you're
technically holding it for two days
almost. So swap and all that stuff will
add up or it'll eat into your profit,
right? So no trades on Sundays. And the
second is going to be no trades from
Thursday onward because everything after
Thursday, think about it, if let's say
you're going to be taking a day trade
approach and let's say you have a 20 pip
stop-loss and then you have a 60 pip
takeprofit. Oh, you would technically
need uh
>> Yeah, technically you would need a 60
pit take profit for a 1 to three versus
reward.
>> Yeah,
>> you probably won't have any volume that
will get the trade to hit those 60 pips
after New York session on Thursday. M
>> so if you do not enter your trade by 8
in the morning or latest 9 in the
morning Thursday you cannot take a trade
because you simply will not have enough
volume to make that trade reach your
takerit before it hits.
>> Yeah.
>> Does that make sense?
>> Yes.
>> So this is to save yourself money and be
in a slow trade. And this is to save
yourself from the trade potentially not
hitting your takeprofit.
>> Yeah. These are two of my secrets when
it comes to when to enter a trade and
when to not. So your main focus is
Monday through technically
Wednesday London session. These are the
most volatile days that you want to
focus on anyways. So when it comes to
your entries, you said from Monday to
Wednesday, but when is the best time?
because you was you was talking about
volume but volume in my understanding
the volume kicks on London and New York
for you which section is the best or it
doesn't matter you only look for the
setup when isn't on area of interest or
you exactly wait on London to take a
trade without no setups. So
>> it's a great question. Great question.
So, I guess a third tip could be if you
want to have your trade hit your takerit
the fastest, yeah,
>> it would be focus on entering your
trades on London session.
>> Now, the reason why is because if you
take a trade in London session, let's
say you take it at 1:00 in the morning,
right? We're talking about EST, right?
So 1:00 a.m. you take the trade. You
have 1:00 a.m. 2:00 a.m. 3:00 a.m. 4:00
a.m. 5:00 a.m. 6 7 8 9 10 and 11 in the
morning where you have full volume
>> full volume in all of these sessions. So
as soon as you enter your trade on
London session your trade is moving to
your takeprofit or your stop loss
>> immediately from once it starts. If you
take a trade in New York session, you
will have a couple of hours of session,
but then after this, you have Tokyo and
Sydney session that will hit as soon as
market closes. And then you're basically
waiting until the volume kicks back in
at the beginning of London session.
>> So for me, when it comes to the account
flips, the best trades that you can
possibly ask for, whether it's Monday,
Tuesday, Wednesday, is to take it at
London session or before London session.
The earliest that I would take a trade
it would could be anywhere from 11 pm
EST onwards. So almost midnight for you.
>> So this is a great question and this
this is a hack because you get the full
volume
>> back to back. So other question is when
when your trades hit TP, let's say you
enter Monday and Tuesday, your trade
hits TP, you done for the week or you
you keep looking for more trades or more
setups during the week? That's a great
question and that is what would come
down to an experienced trader to make a
decision on. And there's some times
where calling it quits as soon as you
win a trade is the right thing to do.
There's also where it's the wrong thing
where you might miss out on another
opportunity. The way I like to look at
it is a great business opportunity
doesn't come every single week,
>> right? If you if you're going to invest
into a great company, a great startup,
it's not going to come every single
week, right? They'll come every once in
a while. And I like to look at trading
very similar to that. A great trade
won't come every single week.
>> Yeah.
>> So to answer that question, it would
have to directly go to where are you in
your account, right? So, let's say for
example, once again, we started off the
account with the $1,000 and let's say we
won our first trade risking $250.
Now, we're up $1,750, [music]
right? So, our account right now is at
$1,750
and we won our trade and it's Tuesday
[music] afternoon. We entered the trade
Monday London session, hit take profit.
By Tuesday, we still have Tuesday,
[music] Wednesday, Thursday, Friday for
the market to move into our takerit.
Should you go ahead and enter another
trade or not? Now, this is where it's
going to completely be decided up to the
trader.
>> I don't believe that you should just
say, "Oh, one and done and that's it.
I'm done for the week." Or, "If I lose a
trade, I'm done for the week. If I win a
trade, I'm done for the week." I believe
if there's an opportunity, you take it
because you don't know when another
opportunity will come again.
>> Awesome. So that really is going to be
up to the trader and [music] what you
are comfortable with risking because
maybe there's another great opportunity
that presents itself in Wednesday and
then you don't have another trade for
another two weeks that go by and the
your only opportunity was on Wednesday.
So putting this fixed rule on such a
unfixed industry because the market is
so random, right? It it just moves
random in every single day. I don't
think it's
I think it's more of like a superstition
to people
>> like you shouldn't base your personal
results on your trade on the
opportunities that the market gives you.
So like if if you won a trade or not
that doesn't affect the opportunities
that the market's going to give you.
>> The market doesn't care. It doesn't know
if you won or lost. It [music] doesn't
matter. So whether you win or lose that
next opportunity was going to present
itself no matter what. You just have to
be ready to [music] make the decision to
enter that trade and if it makes sense
to enter it or not. So
>> to answer your question, that would be
directly [music] to what you feel most
comfortable with.
>> That's a great question.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So now understanding some of
the secrets to scale a small account.
These are some of my secret traits that
I carry under my sleeve.
>> Let's talk about some things that you
might really run into, okay?
>> Which is almost inevitable. And that's
going to be the mind. The mind, right?
All right, we're going to draw a little
brain here. Uh, it's a terrible brain.
That's the brain, right? Which is going
to be the psychology
of a trader. This is what will make
or break
you and
>> your money
>> and your money [laughter] and your small
account, your big account, your every
account. You can have everything in
check. And if your mind is not properly
set up, you're cooked. And I'm sure
every single trader can attest to this.
And I'm just going to write down things
that don't help your psychology, right?
These are things that can make maybe
make you feel better, but if anything,
it does you more damage than good. So
these are things that are not good
for your psychology. One is going to be
motivation. motivation.
>> Motivation is not good because it's
temporary. [music]
>> Yeah.
>> It only lasts a short period of time.
And the moment that you don't have that
motivation, you seek the motivation once
again and it actually ends up digging
you into a deeper hole because it's this
endless never satisfied cycle that you
need to chase. It's almost like once you
are
like let's say once you're into drugs,
right? Like once you get off of it, you
need to get back on it. That that's what
motivation is. It's a drug. It's not
good because it ends up messing with
your mind.
>> Okay.
>> Another thing that is not good is FOMO.
>> Fear of missing out. Your goal here is
to scale a small account. If you're
watching this video and you're still all
the way at this point, you know, you're
not here going to create generational
wealth with $10 or $1,000 or even
$10,000.
So, don't get fear of missing out if you
miss out on some opportunities. Let's
say you're being very selective on the
trades that you want to take and you
wait for certain extra confirmations and
you don't take the trade for whatever
reason and you miss out on it. Don't
think that the next trade is going to
leave you as well because you're waiting
for an extra confirmation and if it
leaves you, it leaves you. If it
doesn't, it doesn't. You move on to the
next trade. [music]
>> Do not have fear of missing out. Will
you miss out on opportunities? [music]
100%. You watching this video right now,
I can almost assure that you haven't
been trading more than 5 years, right? I
can almost assure you that. And just to
let you know, you've been missing out on
opportunities in the markets for the
last 25 years. So if you just missed a
trade this week or next week or the
following week, think about all the
other opportunities that you've missed
out on for the last two, three decades
that the market has been presenting.
>> So are you really missing out on
something? No. These are all new
opportunities being presented to you,
and they're not going to stop. What will
stop you from capitalizing off of these
next opportunities [music] is your mind
on fear missing out while you're going
to chase trades. Next is the classic
greed. I wanted to take the $1,000 to
$10,000 and you get there and you're
like, well, that was easy. Now I want to
take it to a million. And then what
ended up happening? You end up upping
your risk. you end up taking more
trades, forgetting what you did to get
you to the point that got you to your
current account balance [music] and then
you blow your account.
>> Yeah.
>> Be content with what you have done. Now,
I'm not saying be satisfied or celebrate
or be happy, but realize and have a
moment of realization. It's like, "Holy
I [music] just did something that
99% of the population can't do." 99% of
the population can't even look at a
chart and understand if it's going up or
down. Mhm.
>> And if you can already withdraw some
money from that, you're already ahead of
the game by 99%. If not almost 100. So
greed at any given points, don't feel
the need to risk more to make more. If
you know how to read the charts and you
know how to find solid opportunities,
the money will come. It will take time.
It's not going to come from one second
to another, but the money will come.
Greed is what is going to then fund your
emotional
decisions. I'm sure we've all been there
when either we've gotten into a fight
with a girlfriend, when something is
going on with, you know, a family
member, um whether they are supporting
you or not. Parents could be fighting,
>> whatever is going on in your life,
right? Lead you to make an emotional
decision. Oh, I need to make this money
right now because you know what? I want
to get out of the house or I want to
show this person that I'm worthy of this
or I want to do this. Any decision that
you're making a trade [music] based off
of how you feel is already a loss.
>> If anything is based off of how you
feel, you're cooked. You're completely
toasted, right? You can only take a
trade based off of what the market is
telling you. And if the market tells you
it's a good trade, you [music] take it.
It's not what you want to feel towards
the trade.
>> Next, we have probably the most
important. Well, they're all very
important. Procrastination.
You know what? On my next trade, so you
take your first trade, you take a loss,
and you're like, you know what, the next
trade it's not going to it's going to
it's going to be a protrend trade. It's
not going to be a counter trend trade.
>> You realize that a protrend trade could
take some time to get ready. Might take
one or two days, and then you get
entertained in the between by a counter
trend trade. You take it and then you
lose again. Then go, you know what, the
next trade I'll risk a little bit more
and actually make it a protrend trade.
>> You take that protren trade, you happen
to take a loss as well. and now you're
mad at life as to, you know, why you're
not successfully scaling your small
account.
>> It's because you're procrastinating the
foundation of how to scale a small
account properly.
>> If you say that you're going to go out
there and do something, just do it.
>> Don't procrastinate as to something
needs to happen in order for you to do
something. Mhm.
>> Oh, I need to get a raise at my job in
order for me to start or I need to
[music]
be in a certain time zone to be able to
learn how to do this. No, when you find
the time you do it and you get with it,
but the more you procrastinate, the
longer all of this is going to build
[music] up inside of your mind because
you're going to be seeing other people
capitalizing off of this opportunity and
then you're not. And now you're just
going to like everything here is just
literally going to 2x [music] because
you've been procrastinating for who
knows how long to do the right things
that you know you should be doing. You
know you should be okay with risking a
certain amount of money. You know you
have to stick to that percentage and you
know you have to learn a strategy. It's
very simple. Don't procrastinate on
things that you already know. You're
seeing it every single day online of
people explaining the foundations about
it. But if you procrastinate simple
things like, "Oh, okay. When I get back
home, I'll do my bed or I'm going to
wash the dishes and okay, when I get
back home later, I'll throw out the
trash." All of these small things that
you procrastinate that could get done in
honestly less than 2 minutes. Takes you
2 minutes to do your bed. Takes you 2
minutes to wash the dishes, 1 minute to
throw out the trash. When you get back
home from work or from whatever it is
that you're doing, your mind is clogged
with all of these other micro things
that you didn't do and now you put an
excuse. You procrastinate as to why you
can't get started or as to why you can't
do something because you procrastinate
on doing things on your personal life
that then get involved with [music] this
new side hustle that you want to join or
this new business that you want to
start. All because small things that
you've done have built up to hold you
back from what you actually want to do.
So don't procrastinate anything
anything.
Now all of this built up will literally
be equal
to you. This is going to be the direct
representation of who you are. If you as
a person to people or you as a person
are emotional, you as a person are
greedy, all of that is going to reflect
to the markets and it's going to come
back to you two times fold. So you need
to approach the markets as a trader. And
I I say this all the time. For you to go
out there and become a bodybuilder, what
do you have to do?
>> Well, you have to become a bodybuilder.
You have to go to the gym. You have to
eat like an animal, follow strict diet,
count your macros, hit the cardio, take
maybe some enhancing supplements, right?
>> Right. If you want to be a bodybuilder,
you have to do what it takes to be a
bodybuilder.
>> If you want to be a trader, you have to
do what it takes to be a trader. You
have to turn into a trader. You have to
be okay with taking risk. You have to be
okay with staying up late. You have to
be okay with not even making money at
times because that's just how it goes.
The same day you walk into the gym is
not the same day you get abs. It's just
not how it works. Now, with that being
said, we have discussed some pretty core
foundations of any trader. Whether you
want to have $1,000, $10,000, or
$100,000, a million dollar accounts that
you [music] want to scale at a slow
rate, at a fast rate, you need to have
these key foundations. You need to have
your core plan. You need to have a
certain approach on how you're going to
approach it. You need to have a risk
management because without that, there's
no longevity on how you're going to
scale the account. And then most
importantly, you need to have a
strategy. A strategy that is going to
let you understand when it's the right
time to take a trade and when it's the
right time to not you can take on
literally him. This dude did not know
how to trade previously. He learned the
strategy. And so how much are you up
this month? Right now?
>> This month? Um 41,000
>> on your profit account?
>> Yeah. 41,000.
>> Now, we got to get you to your personal
account so you can scale this. So,
you're going to deposit those 41,000 in
your personal or you going to take a
piece of that?
>> Probably a piece like 20K.
>> 20K.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, cool. So, you technically fall
under the small account. So, you could
still do something pretty aggressive
like this.
>> But without a strategy,
>> he would have never had the type of
resources that he has now to be able to
not only scale a profit account and now
attack his personal account. You guys
want to learn a strategy? get on calls
with me and other [music] students just
like himself where we review your
trades, see what you're doing wrong,
double down on what you're doing right.
Click the link in description down
below. We'll break down for you exactly
the trades that we're interested in
trading [music] for the week and letting
you guys know what you're doing wrong
and be part of a winning community. You
guys are going to want to know more
about it. Hit the link in the
description below. Hope you guys enjoyed
this video. Make sure to hit that like
and subscribe button. See you guys in
the next one. Don't
>> forget. to you guys.